<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Resume xmlns="http://ns.hr-xml.org/2007-04-15">
   <StructuredXMLResume>
      <ContactInfo>
         <PersonName>
            <GivenName>Deneena</GivenName>
            <FamilyName>Lanius</FamilyName>
         </PersonName>
         <ContactMethod>
            <Mobile>253-670-3550</Mobile>
            <InternetEmailAddress>Laniusd@avalonconsult.com</InternetEmailAddress>
         </ContactMethod>
      </ContactInfo>
      <EmploymentHistory>
         <EmployerOrg>
            <EmployerOrgName>Avalon Consulting LLC</EmployerOrgName>
            <PositionHistory positionType="contract">
               <Title>Senior Consultant</Title>
               <OrganizationName>ADEPTCentral</OrganizationName>
               <Description>
                  <p>Ms. Lanius is responsible for the successful delivery of learning solutions to ADEPTCentral clients, overseeing critical facets of practice management such as strategic planning, quality assurance, best practices, and client relationship management.</p>
                  <p>As an Enterprise Learning Strategist), Ms. Lanius participates in all stages of learning projects as needed, with heavy involvement in the strategy, design, and planning phases. She applies ADEPTCentral's ADEPT methodology to transition clients from instructor-led training to online, or to improve their current learning and delivery environments. A few of the notable learning projects led by Ms. Lanius include:</p>
               </Description>
               <StartDate>1000-01-01</StartDate>
            </PositionHistory>
            <PositionHistory positionType="contract">
               <Title>Senior Consultant</Title>
               <OrganizationName>Concorde Career College</OrganizationName>
               <Description>
                  <p>Concorde Career College offers over 20+ programs in the area of healthcare. Due to the demand for online programs, Concorde Career College partnered with ADEPTCentral and adopted the ADEPT Program to assist restructuring current classes to 100% online. As the Senior ADEPT Program Consultant Ms. Lanius has assisted Concorde with the following milestones:</p>
                  <ul>
                     <li>Define and develop a comprehensive
                end-user based Standards and Best Practices
                document that will help professors rapidly design
                and develop Concorde's online programs ensuring
                that each course will be built in accordance to
                Concorde's standards. The Standards and Best
                Practices document ensures that each course is
                educationally sound, meets student's demands as it
                relates to accessibility and manageability,
                leverages Concorde's LMS system and its full
                functionality, and meets accreditation
                requirements.</li>
                     <li>Developed, maintained and managed
                a master schedule plan to develop three healthcare
                programs: Bachelors of Nursing, Healthcare
                Administration and General Core Education that
                include nearly 60 courses.</li>
                     <li>Using the ADEPT Program
                methodology, Ms. Lanius successfully onboard over
                30 professors to assist in the restructure of the
                lesson plans to ensure that the online courses meet
                the need of each student and course goals that had
                previously been accredited standards.
                </li>
                  </ul>
               </Description>
               <StartDate>1000-01-01</StartDate>
            </PositionHistory>
            <PositionHistory positionType="contract">
               <Title>Senior Consultant</Title>
               <OrganizationName>Cambria-Rowe Business College</OrganizationName>
               <Description>
                  <p>Cambria-Rowe, for over a century, has educated students in specialized fields of study that result in graduates who are knowledgeable and skilled. Their mission is to transition their traditional classrooms to a blended format offering more flexibility and access to students. Using the ADEPT methods, Ms. Lanius successfully on-boarded over 20 teachers/instructors to the ADEPT rapid development process that helped them quickly transition their classroom training to online. Teachers learned how to flip their lessons plans so that the students could access the reading, lecture and other comprehensive materials online and use the classroom for the applied, application level homework and assignments.</p>
               </Description>
               <StartDate>1000-01-01</StartDate>
            </PositionHistory>
            <PositionHistory positionType="contract">
               <Title>Senior Consultant</Title>
               <OrganizationName>University of North Carolina</OrganizationName>
               <Description>
                  <p>The Kenan-Flagler School of Business launched their first online business certification program, designed to provide non-business majors a competitive edge for job placement in the marketplace. The program educates non-business majors in the areas of finance, accounting, business acumen and communications. The program, designed to gain reach in the market, created an additional revenue stream for UNC. Using the ADEPT method, Ms. Lanius:</p>
                  <ul>
                     <li>Led the project through an
                extensive needs analysis that resulted in an online
                curriculum with specific objectives designed to
                help non-business major succeed in a corporate
                environment  </li>
                     <li>Assisted UNC e-Learning
              Specialists and Professors in launching theKenan-Flagler Business
              Essentials Certification Program in a rapid timeframe of five
              months</li>
                     <li>Guided the directors &amp;
                professors of Kenan-Flagler in the optimal use of
                their online technologies to ensure successful
                implementation and delivery to potential students,
                resulting in revenue gains for UNC</li>
                  </ul>
               </Description>
               <StartDate>1000-01-01</StartDate>
            </PositionHistory>
            <PositionHistory positionType="contract">
               <Title>Senior Consultant</Title>
               <OrganizationName>Catholic Health Initiatives (CHI)</OrganizationName>
               <Description>
                  <p>CHI needed to implement a learning management system (LMS) nationwide, a major initiative that included nearly 70 hospitals and clinics hosting courses online where employees can track and measure training. Ms. Lanius'contribution entailed:</p>
                  <p>Worked with the Director of Learning Effectiveness to develop and deploy an implementation roadmap, which included areas of employee data transfer, standards/best practices for content development, and role-based training on the usage of the LMS</p>
               </Description>
               <StartDate>1000-01-01</StartDate>
            </PositionHistory>
            <PositionHistory positionType="contract">
               <Title>Senior Consultant</Title>
               <OrganizationName>Cooper Clinic</OrganizationName>
               <Description>
                  <p>Cooper Clinic, a health and wellness corporation, decided to move their flagship-training program,</p>
                  <p>Professional Fitness Trainer Program,</p>
                  <p>online. Ms. Lanius' tasks included:</p>
                  <ul>
                     <li>Conducted an assessment of their
                existing learning environment, clients,
                technologies and training program</li>
                     <li>From this assessment, developed a
                proof of concept for the new online environment
                that provided a clear vision of how Cooper could
                gain additional revenue through online
                training</li>
                     <li>Led the e-Learning consultant team
                in identifying strengths and weaknesses of Cooper
                Clinic's initiative</li>
                  </ul>
               </Description>
               <StartDate>1000-01-01</StartDate>
            </PositionHistory>
            <PositionHistory positionType="contract">
               <Title>Senior Consultant</Title>
               <OrganizationName>Hewlett-Packard (HP)</OrganizationName>
               <Description>
                  <p>As a consultant and senior instructional designer, Ms. Lanius:</p>
                  <p>Led a design team through the ADEPT process to provide multiple course curriculums for HP's client software product training</p>
                  <p>This product training was designed to be generic, yet easy to customize for specific client implementations of HP software</p>
                  <p>Developed standards for the base online training product to ensure consistency and rapid development of training products</p>
               </Description>
               <StartDate>1000-01-01</StartDate>
            </PositionHistory>
            <PositionHistory positionType="contract">
               <Title>Senior Consultant</Title>
               <OrganizationName>National Vision</OrganizationName>
               <Description>
                  <p>National Vision, a national optical corporation, had implemented an LMS system, yet was struggling to transition legacy training to the new system. Ms. Lanius:</p>
                  <ul>
                     <li>Provided consultation in the area
                of catalog development, curriculum management and
                content transitioning</li>
                     <li>Identified weaknesses in their
                environment, such as low bandwidth and outdated
                computer systems</li>
                     <li>Created a roadmap for developing
                role-based training, succession planning, catalog
                and content development and recommendations for
                removing environmental access restrictions</li>
                  </ul>
               </Description>
               <StartDate>1000-01-01</StartDate>
            </PositionHistory>
            <PositionHistory positionType="contract">
               <Title>Senior Consultant</Title>
               <OrganizationName>Two Men and a Truck</OrganizationName>
               <Description>
                  <p>Two Men and a Truck, a large national moving firm, experienced a high volume of turnover and wanted to use their current Learning Management System (LMS) to speed up the delivery cycle for training new employees. This initiative also included Franchise access and best practices for using and deploying training through the centralized LMS system. Ms. Lanius' responsibilities included:</p>
                  <ul>
                     <li>Collaborated with the Director of
                Training, LMS Administrator and Senior
                Instructional Designers to provide advanced
                training on LMS functionality</li>
                     <li>Guided the Director of Training in
                developing a long- term improvement plan for the
                company's training initiative</li>
                  </ul>
               </Description>
               <StartDate>1000-01-01</StartDate>
            </PositionHistory>
         </EmployerOrg>
      </EmploymentHistory>
      <EducationHistory/>
      <Qualifications>
         <Competency abbrev="ms-office">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>MS Office</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="presenter">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>Presenter</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="engage">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>Engage</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="quizmaker">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>Quizmaker</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="storyline">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>Storyline</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="adobe-captivate">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>Adobe Captivate</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="vignette">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>Vignette</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="dreamweaver">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>Dreamweaver</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="fireworks">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>Fireworks</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="flash">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>Flash</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
         <Competency abbrev="html">
            <CompetencyDisplayName>HTML</CompetencyDisplayName>
            <YearsExperience>0</YearsExperience>
         </Competency>
      </Qualifications>
   </StructuredXMLResume>
</Resume>
